Guide to the Vanguard Press Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Vanguard Press Records,
ca.1925-ca.1985
Vanguard Press.
134 linear ft. (227 boxes and 22 preservation cases).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscripts Library, Butler Library, New York, NY, 10027.
4079730
History
Established with money out of the Garland Fund in 1926, the Vanguard Press under the editorial guidance of James Henle and Evelyn Shrifte established and maintained a reputation for publishing promising new fiction writers, as well as informed and challenging nonfiction. In the fall of 1988, Vanguard Press was sold to Random House.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of the editorial and production archives of Vanguard Press: correspondence, manuscripts, contracts, memoranda, galley proofs, photographs, clippings, and printed materials. The correspondence and editorial files contain a wealth of detailed information about individual authors and the growth and development of the Press. Among the cataloged correspondents are: Nelson Algren, Saul Bellow, Stephen Vincent Benét, William Rose Benét; Phyllis Bottome; Pierre Boulle; Jocelyn Brooke; Cyril Connolly; A.J. Cronin; Nigel Dennis; John Dewey; Max Eastman; James T. Farrell; Vardis Fisher; Richard Garnett; Theodor Seuss Geisel; Louis Golding; Paul Goodman; Horace Gregory; Geoffrey Grigson; Lillian Hellman; William Heyen; Harold L. Ickes; Christopher Isherwood; Alfred Kazin; Philip Lamantia; Sinclair Lewis; Emanuel Litvinoff; Dwight Macdonald; Archibald MacLeish; Marshall McLuhan; Thomas Mann; Edgar Lee Masters; H. L. Mencken; William Meredith; Joyce Carol Oates; Katherine Anne Porter; Barbara Pym; William Sansom; William Saroyan; Ramon J. Sender; Upton Sinclair; Rex Stout; Edith Sitwell; Paul Theroux; Lionel Trilling; Harry S. Trumam; Louis Untermeyer; Eudora Welty; Richard Wilbur; and Thornton Wilder. There are some manuscripts by Bellow; Bottome; Boulle; Farrell; Grigson; Litvinoff; MacDonald; Oates; John Cowper Powys; Arthur Schlesinger, Jr.; Patrick Tanner; William Targ; Theroux; and Sitwell.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 8 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
Series III: Joyce Carol Oates Galleys
Series IV: Cataloged Artwork
Series V: Cataloged Photographs
Series VI: Editorial Files
Series VII: Photographs
Series VIII: Clippings
Subjects
Algren, Nelson, 1909-1981.; Bellow, Saul.; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943.; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950.; Bottome, Phyllis, 1884-1963.; Boulle, Pierre, 1912-1994.; Brown, Claude, 1937-; Brooke, Jocelyn.; Burnett, Whit, 1899-1973.; Campbell, Joseph, 1904-1987.; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971.; Connolly, Cyril, 1903-1974.; Cronin, A. J. (Archibald Joseph), 1896-1981.; Dennis, Patrick, 1921-1976.; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969.; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979.; Field, Sara Bard, 1882-1974.; Fisher, Vardis, 1895-1968.; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958.; Ford, Charles Henri.; Fuchs, Daniel, 1909-1993.; Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1905-1995.; Garnett, Richard, 1923-; Seuss,--Dr.; Godwyn, Fay.; Golding, Louis, 1895-1958.; Goodman, Paul, 1911-1972.; Gregory, Horace, 1898-1982.; Grigson, Geoffrey, 1905-1985.; Held, John, 1889-1958.; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984.; Henle, James.; Heyen, William, 1940-; Hook, Sidney, 1902-1989.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952.; Ignatow, David, 1914-1997.; Isherwood, Christopher, 1904-1986.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kazin, Alfred, 1915-1998.; Koestler, Arthur, 1905-1983.; Komroff, Manuel, 1890-1974.; Krementz, Jill.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; Lamantia, Philip, 1927-2005.; Lerner, Max, 1902-1992.; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951.; Litvinoff, Emanuel.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1902-1985.; Loveman, Amy.; Macdonald, Dwight.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; McLuhan, Marshall, 1911-1980.; Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955.; Markova, Alicia, Dame, 1910-2004.; Masters, Edgar Lee, 1868-1950.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Meredith, William, 1911-; Nearing, Scott, 1883-1983.; Oates, Joyce Carol, 1938-; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980.; Powys, John Cowper, 1872-1963.; Price, Arthur.; Pym, Barbara.; Randall, Tony.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Sansom, William.; Saroyan, William, 1908-1981.; Schapiro, Meyer, 1904-1996.; Schlesinger, Arthur M. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007.; Schrifte, Evelyn.; Sender, Ramón José, 1901-1982.; Shiel, M. P. (Matthew Phipps), 1865-1947.; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968.; Stout, Rex Todhunter.; Sitwell, Edith, Dame, 1887-1964.; Sitwell, Osbert, 1892-1969.; Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1897-1988.; Stein, Sol.; Stout, Rex, 1886-1975.; Symington, Stuart, 1901-1988.; Targ, William, 1907-; Theroux, Paul.; Trease, Geoffrey, 1909-1998.; Trilling, Lionel, 1905-1975.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tyler, Paul.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Van Doren, Carl, 1885-1950.; Wallenstein, Alfred.; Welty, Eudora, 1909-2001.; Wilbur, Richard, 1921-; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975.; American literature.; Authors, American.; Literature.; Publishers and publishing.; Clippings.; Contracts.; Galley proofs.; Memoranda.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Authors.; Novelists.; Poets.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
Records Gift
Gift of Random House, 1989.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Algren, Nelson
  - Bellow, Saul
  - Benét, Stephen Vincent
  - Benét, William Rose.
  - Bettelheim, Bruno
  - Bottome, Phyllis..
  - Boulle, Pierre
  - Brooke, Jocelyn
  - Brown, Claude
  - Burnett, Whit
  - Campbell, Joseph
  - Cerf, Bennett A.
  - Connolly, Cyril
  - Cronin, Archibald Joseph
  - Dennis, Nigel
  - Dennis, Patrick
  - Dewey, John
  - Douglas, Melvyn
  - Eastman, Max
  - Farrell, James T.
  - Field, Sara Bard
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield
  - Fisher, Vardis
  - Ford, Charles Henri
  - Fuchs, Daniel
  - Fulbright, J. William
  - Garnett, Richard
  - Geisel, Theodor Seuss
  - Golding, Louis
  - Goodman, Paul
  - Gregory, Horace
  - Grigson, Geoffrey
  - Held, John, Jr.
  - Hellman, Lillian
  - Heyen, William
  - Hook, Sidney
  - Ickes, Harold L.
  - Ignatow, David
  - Isherwood, Christopher
  - Kazin, Alfred
  - Koestler, Arthur
  - Komroff, Manuel
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello H.
  - Lamantia, Philip
  - LeClerq, Jacques
  - Lerner, Max
  - Lewis, Sinclair
  - Litvinoff, Emanuel
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr.
  - Loveman, Amy
  - Macdonald, Dwight
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - McLuhan, Marshall
  - Mann, Thomas
  - Markova, Alicia
  - Masters, Edgar Lee
  - Mencken, Henry Louis
  - Meredith, William
  - Nearing, Scott
  - Norton, W. W.
  - Oates, Joyce Carol
  - Porter, Katherine Anne
  - Price, Arthur
  - Pym, Barbara
  - Randall, Tony
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
  - Sansom, William
  - Saroyan, William
  - Schapiro, Meyer
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr.
  - Sender, Ramon J.
  - Shafer, Burr
  - Shiel, M. P.
  - Sinclair, Upton
  - Sitwell, Edith, Dame
  - Sitwell, Osbert
  - Sitwell, Sacheverell
  - Stein, Sol
  - Stout, Rex Todhunter
  - Symington, Stuart
  - Theroux, Paul
  - Trease, Geoffrey
  - Trilling, Lionel
  - Truman, Harry S.
  - Tyler, Parker
  - Untermeyer, Louis
  - Van Doren, Carl
  - Van Doren, Irita
  - Wallenstein, Alfred
  - Welty, Eudora
  - Wilbur, Richard
  - Wilder, Thornton
  - Zaturenska, Marya
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
  - Bellow, Saul
  - Bottome, Phyllis
  - Boulle, Pierre
  - Farrell, James T.
  - Grigson, Geoffrey
  - Litvinoff, Emanuel
  - Macdonald, Dwight
  - Oates, Joyce Carol
  - Powys, John Cowper
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr.
  - Tanner, Patrick
  - Targ, William
  - Theroux, Paul
  - Sitwell, Edith, Dame
- Series III: Joyce Carol Oates Galleys
  This is a group of 22 boxes of galley sheets and page proof of many of her novels
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Assassins, [n.p.], 23 July 1975, ([ca. 194p.] galley sheets) (Box 397)
    [With the author's and editor's ms. corrections]
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Assassins, [n.p.], 28 August 1975, ([ca. 200p.] galley sheets) (Box 397)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Assassins, [n.p.], 9 October 1975, ([ca. 200p.] galley sheets) (Box 397)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Assassins, [n.p.], 1975, ([ca. 150p.] page proof) (Box 405)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Childwold, [n.p.], July 1976, ([ca. 292p.] galley sheets) (Box 408)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Childwold, [n.p.], 30 July 1976, ([ca. 116p.] galley sheets) (Box 408)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Childwold, [n.p.], 1976, ([ca. 150p.] page proof) (Box 392)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Crossing the Border, [n.p.], 12 March 1976, ([ca. 87p.] galley sheets) (Box 390)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Crossing the Border, [n.p.], 3 May 1976, ([ca. 256p.] galley sheets) (Box 390)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Crossing the Border, [Windsor, Ontario], [March 1976], (13p. galley sheets)
    [With corrections & changes in her hand; sheets are partly photocopies]
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Do With Me What You Will, [n.p.], 28 April 1973, ([ca. 197p.] galley sheets) (Box 404)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Do With Me What You Will, [n.p.], 10 May 1093, ([ca. 197p.] galley sheets) (Box 404)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Do With Me What You Will, [n.p.], 23 May 1973, ([ca. 115p.] galley sheets) (Box 404)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Do With Me What You Will, [n.p.], 31 May 1973, ([ca. 43p.] galley sheets) (Box 404)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Edge of Impossibility, [n.p.], [ca. 1972], ([ca. 78p.] galley sheets) (Box 399)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Expensive People, [n.p.], [ca. 25 June 1968], ([ca. 85p.] galley sheets) (Box 400)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Garden of Earthly Delights, [n.p.], 1967, ([ca. 150p.] galley sheets) (Box 411)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Goddess and Other Women, [n.p.], 25 July 1974, ([ca. 162p.] galley sheets) (Box 410)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Marriages and Infidelities, [n.p.], 23 May 1972, ([ca. 100p.] galley sheets) (Box 402)
    [With the author's ms. corrections]
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Marriages and Infidelities, [n.p.], 24 May 1972, ([ca. 120p.] galley sheets) (Box 402)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Marriages and Infidelities, [n.p.], 19 June 1972, ([ca. 45p.] galley sheets) (Box 402)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Marriages and Infidelities, [n.p.], 1972, ([ca. 100p.] page proof) (Box 403)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol New Heaven, New Earth, [n.p.], 17 April 1974, ([ca. 50p.] galley sheets) (Box 409)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol New Heaven, New Earth, [n.p.], 28 May 1974, ([ca. 60p.] galley sheets) (Box 409)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Night-side, [n.p.], [n.d.], (10p. page proof) (Box 407)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Night-side, [n.p.], 7 July 1977, ([ca. 197p.] galley sheets) (Box 407)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Poisoned Kiss, [Windsor, Ontario], [April 1975], (3p. Galley sheets)
    ["Afterword" & "Note" photocopies with corrections & notes added in her hand]
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Sacred Marriage, [n.p.], [1972], (21p. galley sheets) (Box 395)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Sacred Marriage, [n.p.], 9 May 1972, (148p. galley sheets) (Box 395)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Son of the Morning, [n.p.], [1978], ([ca. 202p.] galley sheets) (Box 401)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Son of the Morning, [n.p.], [1978], ([ca. 202p.] galley sheets) (Box 406)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Them, [n.p.], 30 June 1969, ([ca. 200p.] galley sheets) (Box 396)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Them, [n.p.], 3 July 1969, ([ca. 167p.] galley sheets) (Box 391)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Unholy Loves, [n.p.], 1 June 1979, ([ca. 166p.] galley sheets) (Box 388)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Upon the Sweeping Flood, [n.p.], 13 December 1965, ([ca. 79p.] galley sheets) (Box 398)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Upon the Sweeping Flood, [n.p.], 28 December 1965, ([ca. 100p.] galley sheets) (Box 398)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Upon the Sweeping Flood, [n.p.], 14 January 1966, ([ca. 79p.] galley sheets) (Box 398)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Wheel of Love, [n.p.], 30 June 1970, ([ca. 120p.] galley sheets) (Box 393)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol The Wheel of Love, [n.p.], 1970, ([ca. 100p.] galley sheets) (Box 389)
    [With the proofreader's annotations]
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Wonderland, [n.p.], [ca. 1971], ([ca. 174p.] galley sheets) (Box 394)
    [With the authors's and editor's ms. corrections]
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Wonderland, [London], [February 1972], (1p. galley sheet)
    [Revised ending with corrections in her hand]
  - Oates, Joyce Carol Wonderland, [London], [February 1972], (1p. galley sheet)
    [With corrections in her hand]
- Series IV: Cataloged Artwork
  - Geisel, Theodor Seuss SEE: Cataloged Correcpondence
- Series V: Cataloged Photographs
  - Godwin, Fay
  - Krementz, Jill
- Series VI: Editorial Files
  - AMA Journal (Box 1)
  - APIA Agency (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Abellie, Raymond (Box 1)
  - Abercrombie, P.B. (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Harry (Box 1)
  - Ace Books (Box 1)
  - Ackart, Robert (Box 1)
  - Adams, Frank (Box 1)
  - Adelemar French Drawings (Box 1)
  - Adler, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Agel, Jerome (Box 1)
  - Agnen, Seth (Box 1)
  - Agree, David & George (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Jean (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Joan (Box 1)
  - Aistrop, Jack (Box 2)
  - Aitmotov, Chingiz (Box 2)
  - Akerly, Ben (Box 2)
  - Albrecht, Otto (Box 2)
  - Aldo, Garzanti (Box 2)
  - Aldrich, Elizabeth (Box 2)
  - Algren, Nelson (Box 2)
  - Alexander, Florence (Box 2)
  - Allan, Mabel Esther (Box 3)
  - Alland, Guy (Box 3)
  - Allen, Robert (Box 3)
  - Allen, Robert (Box 4-7)
  - Allen, Robert (Box 8)
  - Allen, Ruth Finney (Box 8)
  - Almedinger, E.M. (Box 9)
  - Alstrop & McBride (Box 9)
  - Altshuler, Harry (Box 9)
  - Alvin Redman Ltd (Box 9)
  - American Booksellers Assoc. (Box 9)
  - Amiot-Dumont (Box 9)
  - Anderson, Hans C. (Box 9)
  - Anderson, Ian (Box 9)
  - Anderson, Madelyn (Box 9)
  - Anderton, Vera (Box 9)
  - Andre Deutsch Ltd (Box 10)
  - Andrieux, Raymond (Box 10)
  - Asbury, Herbert (Box 10)
  - Ansbro, Cynthia (Box 10)
  - Antek, Samual (Box 10)
  - Arbo, S.J. (Box 10)
  - Arcata Graphics (Box 10)
  - Arthaud & Herbert-Stevens (Box 10)
  - A/S Bookman (Box 10)
  - Ashbaugh, Nancy (Box 11)
  - Aspher, Tony (Box 11)
  - Asscher-Pinkhof, Clara (Box 11)
  - Atkin, Edith (Box 11)
  - Atwood, Wallace W. (Box 11)
  - Aubrey, Vicky (Box 11)
  - Avery, Gillian (Box 11)
  - Axelrad, Edward (Box 11)
  - Aydelotte, Dora (Box 11)
  - Aylen, Leo (Box 11)
  - Baccante, Leonora (Box 12)
  - Bacon, Walter (Box 12)
  - Baer, Barbara (Box 12)
  - Baker, Denys Val (Box 12)
  - Baker, Jacob (Box 12)
  - Baker, Nancy (Box 12)
  - Baker, Nina Brown (Box 12)
  - Baker, Nina Brown (Box 13)
  - Ballantyne, D.W. (Box 13)
  - Bank Street College of Education (Box 13)
  - Banning, Evelyn (Box 13)
  - Banning, Kendall (Mrs) (Box 13)
  - Bantam Books (Box 13)
  - Bantam Books (Box 14)
  - Barker, Arthur (Box 14)
  - Barkham, John (Box 14)
  - Barkley, Jane (Box 14)
  - Barnes, Harry (Box 14)
  - Barrett, James (Box 14)
  - Barrie & Rockcliff Ltd (Box 14)
  - Beard, Charles (Box 14)
  - Bearman, Jane (Box 14)
  - Beaton-Jones, Cynon (Box 14)
  - Beck Engraving Company (Box 15)
  - Beck, Margaret (Box 15)
  - Becker, Maximilian (Box 15)
  - Behrendt, F. (Box 15)
  - Beilenson (Box 15)
  - Bell, Quentin (Box 15)
  - Bellow, Saul (Box 15)
  - Belmont Productions (Box 15)
  - Benasutti Reports (Box 15)
  - Benn, Harold W. (Box 15)
  - Bennett, Lowell (Box 15)
  - Bent, Silas (Box 15)
  - Bent, Silas (Box 16)
  - Bergengruen, Werner (Box 16)
  - Bevan-Brown, M. (Box 16)
  - Bevans, Marks & Barrow (Box 16)
  - Bichowsky, F. Russell (Box 16)
  - Bigline, Marie Enrique (Box 16)
  - Bitker, Bruno (Box 16)
  - Bitker, Marjorie M. (Box 16)
  - Black, Gordon M. (Box 16)
  - Blackburn, Charles (Box 16)
  - Blackwell, Louise (Box 16)
  - Blunden, Godfrey (Box 17)
  - Boals, San (Box 17)
  - Bobbs Merrill Co. (Box 17)
  - Boggs, Ralph (Box 17)
  - Bolster, Evelyn (Box 17)
  - Bolster, Evelyn (Box 18)
  - Bombard, Alain (Box 18)
  - Bortnicker (Box 18)
  - Bosco, Henri (Box 18)
  - Bothwell, Jean (Box 18)
  - Bottome, Phyllis (Box 18)
  - Boulle, Pierre (Box 18)
  - Boulle, Pierre (Box 19)
  - Bowmann, W.E. (Box 20)
  - Boyce, George (Box 20)
  - Bradley, William (Mrs) (Box 20)
  - Brady, Frank (Box 20)
  - Branch, Edgar (Box 20)
  - Brandon, Evan (Box 21)
  - Branston, Brian (Box 21)
  - Brant, Neil (Box 21)
  - Brean, Herbert (Box 21)
  - Brean, Herbert (Box 22)
  - Breinholt, Verna (Box 22)
  - Brinze, Ruth (Box 22)
  - Brindze, Ruth (Box 23)
  - Britt, George (Box 24)
  - Britton, Lionel (Box 24)
  - Brody, Sidney (Box 24)
  - Brooke, Jocelyn (Box 24)
  - Broun & Britt (Box 24)
  - Broun, Heywood (Box 24)
  - Browder, Earl (Box 24)
  - Brown, Warren A. (Box 24)
  - Bruccoli, Matthew (Box 24)
  - Bruce, Robert (Box 24)
  - Bryant, Matt (Box 24)
  - Buchanan, Lamont (Box 24)
  - Buchet, Chastel (Box 24)
  - Buchler, Samuel (Box 24)
  - Bullock, Alan (Box 24)
  - Burch, Mark (Box 24)
  - Burman, Ben L. (Box 24)
  - Burman Catfish Bend (Box 24)
  - Burnett, Constance B. (Box 25)
  - Burnett, Vivian (Box 25)
  - Burns, Robert (Box 25)
  - Brussel-Smith, B. (Box 25)
  - Burress, Jack (Box 25)
  - Burress, John (Box 25)
  - Burton, Maurice (Box 25)
  - Buskin, Judith (Box 25)
  - Calahan, Harold A. (Box 26)
  - Calhoun, Arthur (Box 26)
  - Calin, Hal Jason (Box 26)
  - Callender, Julian (Box 26)
  - Camp, William (Box 26)
  - Campbell, Dorcas (Box 26)
  - Campbell, Eugene (Box 27)
  - Cantor, Ruth (Box 27)
  - Caravel (Box 27)
  - Carriere, Jean (Box 27)
  - Carter, Dyson (Box 27)
  - Carter, Helene (Box 27)
  - Case, Leland (Box 27)
  - Cassou, Jean (Box 27)
  - Castellanos, Rosario (Box 27)
  - Catalogue Conference Notes (Box 27)
  - Cavanah, Frances (Box 27)
  - Cecil, Lord David (Box 27)
  - Centro Mexicano Escritores (Box 27)
  - Ceppos, P. (Box 27)
  - Chamberlain, William H. (Box 27)
  - Chand (Box 28)
  - Chao, Buwei Y. (Box 28)
  - Chanticleer Press (Box 28)
  - Chayes, Sally (Box 28)
  - Chemical Bank (Box 28)
  - Chester, Afred (Box 28)
  - Cheyette, Maurice (Box 28)
  - Chicago Tribunal (Box 28)
  - Chrisfield, Curt (Box 28)
  - Christy & Moore Ltd (Box 28)
  - Clarke-Railsback, Carolyn (Box 28)
  - Clarke, Donald H. (Box 28)
  - Clarke, D.H. (Box 29 & 30)
  - Clarke, John Henrik (Box 31)
  - Clanchet, Jose T. (Box 31)
  - Clements & Burrell (Box 31)
  - Clephan, Palmer E. (Box 31)
  - Clifford, William (Box 31)
  - Close, Robert S. (Box 31)
  - Closs, August (Box 31)
  - Closs, Hannah (Box 31)
  - Cobin, Harold P. (Box 31)
  - Coetzee, J.M. (Box 31)
  - Colby, Frank (Box 32)
  - Colegrove, Kenneth (Box 33)
  - Colonial Press (Box 33)
  - Conklin, Groft (Box 33)
  - Conrad, Sybil Contracts (Box 33)
  - Consolidated Litho Co. (Box 34)
  - Consumers Union (Box 34)
  - Cooney, James (Box 34)
  - Cooper, Brian (Box 34)
  - Cooper, Lettice (Box 34)
  - Coronet Magazine (Box 34)
  - Corsaro, Frank (Box 34)
  - Cosaro, Frank (Box 35)
  - Cory, Irene (Box 35)
  - Cost, March (Box 35)
  - Cost, March (Box 36)
  - Costigan, Edw. P. (Box 36)
  - Cotten, Lee (Mrs) (Box 36)
  - Cousins, Sheila (Box 36)
  - Cox & Black (Box 36)
  - Cox, Beverly (Box 36)
  - Cox, Cynthia (Box 36)
  - Criterion Books (Box 37)
  - Critics Associated (Box 37)
  - Cronin, A.J. (Box 37)
  - Croxford, Leslie (Box 37)
  - Cunningham. William (Box 37)
  - Curtis, Jean-Louis (Box 37)
  - Curtis-Brown, Anne (Box 37)
  - Customs re. imports (Box 37)
  - Danielian, N.R. (Box 37)
  - Daniels, Steven (Box 37)
  - Das, Frieda (Box 37)
  - David, Elizabeth (Box 37)
  - Davis, Dan (Box 37)
  - Davis, Harry (Box 37)
  - Deane, Shirley (Box 37)
  - DeCastro, Josue (Box 37)
  - De la Brete, Jean (Box 38)
  - Dehn, Paul (Box 38)
  - Del Castillo, Janet (Box 38)
  - Denhard & Stewart (Box 38)
  - Dennett, Mary Hare (Box 38)
  - Dennis, Nigel Forbes (Box 38)
  - Dennis, Patrick (Box 38)
  - Denys Jean (Box 38)
  - Denzer, Ann (Box 38)
  - DeRegniers, Beatrice (Box 38)
  - Deren, Maya (Box 39)
  - Derleth, Edward (Box 39)
  - Detective Book Club (Box 39)
  - Devine, Warran D. (Box 39)
  - DeVries, Robert (Box 39)
  - Diaz-Alejandro, Carlos F. (Box 39)
  - Dickens, Charles (Box 39)
  - Dickinson, Roy (Box 39)
  - Diska, Pat (Box 39)
  - Doherty, Frank (Box 39)
  - Doudai, Naomi (Box 39)
  - Douglas & McIntyre (Box 39)
  - Dresser, Jeremy T. (Box 39)
  - Dugdale, Blanche (Box 39)
  - Dunbar, Virginia E. (Box 39)
  - East & West Library (Box 39)
  - Ebenstein, Irving (Box 39)
  - Editions Albin Michel (Box 39)
  - Editions Pierre Horay (Box 39)
  - Les Editions de la Table Ronde (Box 39)
  - Editors Syndicate (Box 39)
  - Edmond Ward Ltd. (Box 39)
  - Edwards, Monica (Box 39)
  - Ehmann, James Monroe (Box 39)
  - Ehrmann, Herbert B. (Box 40)
  - Elliott, John (Box 40)
  - Ellison, Lynne (Box 40)
  - Elton, Lord (Box 40)
  - Emery, Anne (Box 40)
  - Emmonds, Lieut Tom (Box 40)
  - Emrich, Duncan (Box 40)
  - Endore, Guy (Box 41)
  - English, Bill (Box 41)
  - Epstein, Abraham (Box 41)
  - Ernst, Morris (Box 41)
  - Estimates for printing (Box 41)
  - Estoril, Jean (Box 41)
  - Ethridge, Willie Snow (Box 42 & 43)
  - Ethridge, Willie Snow (Box 44)
  - Evans Bros Ltd. (Box 44)
  - Everett, M.S. (Box 44)
  - Falk, Nat (Box 45)
  - Famous Artists Corp (Box 45)
  - Farrar, Straus & Cudahy (Box 45)
  - Farre, Rowena (Box 45)
  - Farrell, James T. (Box 45)
  - Farrell, James T. (Box 46-47b)
    [Audio tape interview of Farrell by Branko Lenski is in Box 46]
  - Fauer, Lewis S. (Box 48)
  - Felton, Harold N. (Box 48)
  - Ferguson, John (Box 48)
  - Ferreira de Castro, Jose (Box 48)
  - Field, Sara Bard (Box 48)
  - Fifield, Flora (Box 48)
  - Figgis & Co. Ltd. (Box 48)
  - Finney, Charles G. (Box 48)
  - Fisher, Vardis (Box 48)
  - Fisher, Vardis (Box 49)
  - Flaiano, Ennio (Box 49)
  - Fleischman, Theo (Box 49)
  - Fleming, Roscoe (Box 49)
  - Fletcher, David (Box 49)
  - Flornoy, Bertrand (Box 49)
  - Foley, Martha (Box 49)
  - Forbes, Tom H. (Box 49)
  - Ford, Charles Henri (Box 49)
  - Ford, Ford Madox (Box 49)
  - Ford, Hugh (Box 49)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 49)
  - Foreign Pub. Service (Box 49)
  - Foundation for Improvement of Housing Arrangements for Official Foreign Personnel Inc. (Box 49)
  - Francis Scott Key (Box 49)
  - Frank, Jane (Box 49)
  - Franklin, Bart (Box 49)
  - Franklin, Ed (Box 50)
  - Franklin, Madeline (Box 50)
  - Franz J Horch Ass. (Box 50)
  - Fraumeni, Pat (Box 50)
  - Frederick Muller Ltd (Box 50)
  - Fredge, F. (Box 50)
  - Freeman, Beatrice (Box 50)
  - Freeman, Ellis (Box 50)
  - French, Herbert (Box 50)
  - Frere, Maud (Box 51)
  - Freud, Martin (Box 51)
  - Freudenthal, Elizabeth (Box 51)
  - Fuchs, Daniel (Box 51)
  - Fuller, Muriel (Box 51)
  - Funt, Allen (Box 51)
  - Gallenkamp, Charles (Box 52)
  - Gant, Roland (Box 52)
  - Garcia, Eleanor (Box 52)
  - Gardner, Jani (Box 52)
  - Garnett, Eve (Box 52)
  - Gaslight Public (Box 52)
  - Gee & Selby (Box 52)
  - Geisel, Theordor (Box 53)
  - George, Gerald (Box 53)
  - Giangiacomo, Peutrinelli (Box 53)
  - Gibbs, Peter (Box 53)
  - Gibson, Margaret (Box 53)
  - Gilboord, Margaret G. (Box 53)
  - Gilford, Duff (Box 53)
  - Gill, Jill (Box 54)
  - Gilles, Daniel (Box 54)
  - Gillett, Margaret (Box 54)
  - Gillon, Philip (Box 54)
  - Gilman, Evelyn (Box 54)
  - Ginn & Company (Box 54)
  - Ginzburg, Natalia (Box 55)
  - Glaser, W.M. (Box 55)
  - Glickman (Box 55)
  - Gluck, Jay (Box 55)
  - Goldberg, Rube (Box 55)
  - Golding, Louis (Box 55)
  - Gollomb, Joseph (Box 55)
  - Goodenow, Earle (Box 56)
  - Goodkind, Larney (Box 56)
  - Goodman, Paul (Box 56)
  - Goodrich, Warren (Box 56)
  - Goodyear, Clelia P. (Box 56)
  - Gordon, Jan (Box 56)
  - Gould, Joe (Box 56)
  - Gould, Mary Earle (Box 56)
  - Graham, Carroll (Box 56)
  - Graham, Garrett (Box 56)
  - Granata, Maria (Box 56)
  - Granger, Kathleen (Box 56)
  - Grattan, Hartley (Box 56)